Guide to the Gerald Robert Vizenor Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2000 Acquisition, 1880-2000; 1960-2000; 69.86; (99 boxes) + 1 cold storage, 2 broadside
  - Chancers
    - Bound typescript with corrections, 2000 Feb 9 (Box 20)
    - Bound typescript marked "final corrections", 1999 Dec (Box 20)
    - Bound typescript marked "second draft", 1999 Aug (Box 20)
    - Second Draft, typescript, 1999 Aug (Box 20)
  - Hotline Healers
    - Almost Browne, typescript, corrected with notes, undated (Box 21)
    - Almost Browne, bound typescript, corrected, 1996 Feb (Box 21)
    - Bound typescript, corrected, 1996 Oct 29 (Box 21)
    - Page proofs, 1997 May 1 (Box 21)
    - Bound typescript with cover letter, 1996 Sep 13 (Box 21)
  - Almost Browne
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Notes, 1988-1989; 2 (Box 21)
  - "Almost a Whole Trickster," typescript, undated (Box 21)
  - "Narrative Chance" and "Trickster Discourse," typescripts and notes, 1986, undated (Box 21)
  - "Trickster Discourse," notes and typescripts, 1986 (Box 21)
  - Narrative Chance, University of New Mexico, Postmodern Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Narrative Chance, copyedited draft, 1986; 3 (Box 21)
  - Ishi and the Wood Ducks
    - Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 21)
    - Bound typescript, 1994 Oct (Box 21)
    - Bound typescript, corrected, 1994 Oct (Box 21)
    - Original six drafts, typescripts, 1994 Oct 8 (Box 21)
  - Ethnic Studies faculty matters, 1994-1997 (Box 22)
  - Curriculum vitae, bound with typescripts and photocopies of selected writings, 1980 Nov (Box 22)
  - Curriculum vitae, bound with typescripts and photocopies of selected writings, 1982 (Box 22)
  - School of American Research, typescript article with correspondence, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Simon Ortiz UCSC lawsuit, 1990-1992; 2 (Box 22)
  - Harkin Lucero lawsuit, 1996-1998 (Box 22)
  - Ishi, articles and correspondence on re: Vizenor's efforts to name Berkeley landmarks after him, 1992-1999 (Box 22)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, 1983 Spring; 2 (Box 22)
  - Chicago Review Vol 39 #3/4, 1993 (Box 22)
  - Order forms for Vizenor books, [1980s] (Box 22)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalogs, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Wesleyan University Press catalog, 1997 (Box 22)
  - Contact Sheets and negatives for various projects, undated; 4 (Box 22)
  - Griever
    - Fiction Collective Prize, illustrations, reviews, correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 23)
    - Griever notes, 1985, undated (Box 23)
    - First revision typescript, 1985 Aug (Box 23)
    - Fiction Collective, correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
    - Early notes, 1983; 2 (Box 23)
    - Notes and outlines, typescript, undated (Box 23)
    - First draft, typescript, corrected, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Trickster of Liberty, typescript, corrected, with brief cover letter, 1988 May (Box 23)
  - Interior Landscapes, typescript with notes, undated (Box 23)
  - Reviews of and by Vizenor, 1978-1988 (Box 23)
  - Paper on Chippewa newspaper of 1887-1889 submitted for Vizenor's master's degree, 1965 Nov (Box 23)
  - Newspaper clippings on Vizenor's father's murder, 1936-1960 (Box 23)
  - Crossbloods, notes, undated (Box 23)
  - Interior Landscapes, notes, 1988-1989; 4 (Box 23)
  - Clippings, notes, typescripts for Interior Landscapes and Dane White case, 1968-1986 (Box 23)
  - Interior Landscapes
    - Query letter, 1988 Aug 18 (Box 23)
    - Final draft, typescript, corrected, 1990 (Box 24)
    - Bound typescript, with a few corrections, [1990] (Box 24)
    - First draft, typescript, undated (Box 24)
    - Completed manuscript, undated (Box 24)
    - Notes, 1989 (Box 24)
  - Griever
    - Publishers, correspondence with incomplete typescript, 1985-1986 (Box 24)
    - Maps and pronunciation notes from China, with notes, [1980s]; 2 (Box 24)
    - Notes, undated (Box 24)
  - The New Press catalog, 1992-1993 (Box 24)
  - Close Up magazine, in German and English, 1992 (Box 24)
  - Novel of the Americas Symposium, Boulder, CO, program, 1992 Sep (Box 24)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalogs, 1990; 2 (Box 24)
  - University Press of New England catalog, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 24)
  - Griever and Bearheart, covers, undated (Box 24)
  - Wordarrows, covers, undated
  - Various titles, covers, undated
  - Covers, proofs and other material, undated
  - University of Oklahoma Press catalog, 1992 (Box 24)
  - Wicazo Sa Review, 1993 Fall (Box 24)
  - Reviews of Crossbloods and Interior Landscapes, passage from Manifest Manners in The Native American Press, 1990-1993 (Box 24)
  - Native Peoples magazine, including poetry by Vizenor, 1993 Spring (Box 24)
  - Social Research, including an essay by Vizenor, 1995 Fall (Box 24)
  - Religion and Literature, including a short story by Vizenor, 1994 Spring (Box 24)
  - Announcements, lecture and literary events some featuring Vizenor, 1991-1994 (Box 24)
  - Merope, including article on Vizenor in Italian with letter to him from the author in English, 1990 Dec 31 (Box 24)
  - "Christopher Columbus: Lost Havens in the Ruins of Representation," from American Indian Quarterly, 1992 Fall (Box 24)
  - "The Ruins of Representation," from American Indian Quarterly, 1993 Winter (Box 24)
  - Fiction Collective, including a review of Griever, 1988 Spring (Box 24)
  - North Dakota Quarterly, including a short story by Vizenor, 1985 Spring (Box 24)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalogs, including reviews of The People Named the Chippewa, 1984 Fall (Box 24)
  - "Minnesota Chippewa: Woodland Treaties to Tribal Bingo," from American Indian Quarterly, 1989 Winter (Box 24)
  - Berkeley Summer Research Seminars, brochure and layout boards, 1997 Jul (Box 24)
  - Caliban 12, including an essay by Vizenor, 1993 (Box 24)
  - Caliban 13 and 14, including essays by Vizenor, 1993-1994 (Box 25)
  - Caliban 15, including an essay by Vizenor, 1995 (Box 25)
  - Book Forum, including an excerpt from Four Skin, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Studies in American Indian Literatures, 2 issues with an essay by Vizenor and one about him, 1993-1995 (Box 25)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, 2 issues with a book review by Vizenor and a chapter from The People Named The Chippewa, 1983-1985 (Box 25)
  - Noh Quarter, 1985 Winter (Box 25)
  - Crossbloods and Interior Landscapes, covers; interview with Vizenor from a German periodical, 1995, undated (Box 25)
  - Utne Reader, featuring Vizenor on a list of "100 Visionaries Who Could Change Your Life", 1995 Jan (Box 25)
  - University of Minnesota Press literary poster, undated (Box 25)
  - Red River Valley Historical Review, including a review of Vizenor's Wordarrows, 1980 Winter (Box 25)
  - The Berkeley Poetry Review, including scenes from The Heirs of Columbus, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Poesie Amerindienne, including a Vizenor poem translated into French, 1989 May (Box 25)
  - Genre, introduction by Vizenor, 1992 Winter (Box 25)
  - Melus, two issues, 1981-1986 (Box 25)
  - Literary and Cultural Studies [University of Minnesota Press catalog] with reviews of Griever and Bearheart, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Sur le Dos de la Turtue, including Vizenor essay in French, 1991 Jan (Box 25)
  - Tamaqua, Native American Issue, 1991 Winter (Box 25)
  - Squaw Valley Writers' Workshop brochures, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - "Native American Indian Identities: Autoinscriptions and the Cultures of Names," from Genre, 1992 Winter (Box 25)
  - Introduction to Genre XXV, by Vizenor and Alan R. Velie, 1992 Winter (Box 25)
  - "Minnesota Chippewa: Woodland Treaties to Tribal Bingo," from American Indian Quarterly, 1989 Winter (Box 25)
  - Boundary, including an excerpt from Manifest Manners, 1992 Fall (Box 25)
  - American Indian Quarterly, including an essay by Vizenor, 1993 Winter (Box 25)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, two issues including an essay and a book review by Vizenor, 1983-1985 (Box 25)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, two issues including essays by Vizenor, 1992 (Box 25)
  - Studio One, including a poem by Vizenor, 1976 Spring (Box 25)
  - American Studies Exchange, including a review of Earthdivers, 1982 Spring (Box 25)
  - Film Quarterly, 1981 Summer (Box 25)
  - "Firewater Labels and Methodologies," from The American Indian Quarterly, 1983 Fall (Box 25)
  - Dacotah Territory, including poems by Vizenor, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Canto General, play program, 1985 Aug 25 (Box 25)
  - Wesleyan University Press catalog, including brief descriptions of The Heirs of Columbus and Landfill Meditation, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Weber Studies, including an interview with Vizenor, 1999 Winter (Box 25)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, including a Vizenor article, 1989 Winter (Box 25)
  - Caliban 6 and 7, including a Vizenor essay and an excerpt from Interior Landscapes, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Caliban 9 (2 copies), including a Vizenor essay, 1990 (Box 25)
  - Roots: On the Reservation, including a Vizenor essay, 1986 (Box 25)
  - Under Construction, 1982 Winter (Box 25)
  - European Review of Native American Studies, sealed, 1990 (Box 25)
  - Minneapolis Department of Indian Education report, including articles by Vizenor, 1977-1978 (Box 25)
  - Twin Citian, with an article by Vizenor about the White Hawk case, 1968 Jun (Box 26)
  - Twin Citian, including an essay by Vizenor, 1966 May (Box 26)
  - University of Nebraska Press catalog, including a profile of Postindian Conversations, 1999 Fall (Box 26)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalog, including a brief profile of Crossbloods, 1991 Spring (Box 26)
  - University Press of New England catalog, including a profile of Landfill Meditations, 1991 Fall (Box 26)
  - American Book Awards program, including a profile of Vizenor and Griever, 1988 (Box 26)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalog, including a profile of The Trickster of Liberty, 1988 Fall (Box 26)
  - University of Oklahoma Press catalog, including a profile of Gerald Vizenor: Writing in the Oral Tradition by Kimberly M. Blaeser, 1996 Fall (Box 26)
  - University of Minnesota Press catalog, including a profile of Growing Up in Minnesota, to which Vizenor contributed, 1989 Fall (Box 26)
  - Beaulieu and Vizenor Families Genealogies, bound typescript by Vizenor, 1983 Jan (Box 26)
  - Chelsea Hotel, two issues including articles by Vizenor, in German, 1992-1993 (Box 26)
  - Chronological Files
    Primarily includes correspondence, as well as some writings and printed material, roughly grouped by year.
    - 1994-1998, 17 (Box 27)
    - 1994-1998, 4 (Box 28)
    - 1983-1986, 10 (Box 28)
    - 1990, 4 (Box 29)
    - 1991 (Box 29)
    - 1994, 6 (Box 29)
    - 1993-1994, 9 (Box 29)
    - (including some material dated 1991-1992), 1993-1994; 32 (Box 30)
    - 1992-1993, 12 (Box 31)
    - 1988-1994, 3 (Box 31)
    - Catalogs and programs, 1988-1992; 2 (Box 31)
    - (including some material dated 1990-1994), 1992; 15 (Box 31)
    - (including some material dated 1991), 1992; 9 (Box 32)
    - 1991, 4 (Box 32)
    - 1992 (Box 32)
    - Santa Cruz inaugural lecture, 1989 Feb 27 (Box 32)
    - (including some material dated 1993-1994), 1995-1996; 27 (Box 33)
    - (including some material dated 1994), 1995-1996; 17 (Box 34)
    - 1988-1989, 4 (Box 34)
    - 1989-1991, 13 (Box 35)
    - 1998-1999, 16 (Box 36)
    - 1987-1988, 4 (Box 36)
    - (including some material dated 1994-1997), 1998-1999; 23 (Box 37)
    - 1998-1999, 11 (Box 38)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1991-1999; 17 (Box 38)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1992-1999; 25 (Box 39)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1996-1997; 9 (Box 40)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 41)
  - Computer disks, (2 computer disks)
    Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information:
    Disk #20000822-y.0005; F99 Vizenor + Lee "Postindian Conversations" EDITED MANUSCRIPT, 15 files – 000 – 99 Vizpos, WP5.1/DOS
    Disk #20000822-y.0006; Vizenor IBM Word Perfect 4.0
  - Posters, rolled (Box 48)
  - Audio material
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Cassettes
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Kimberly M. Blaeser interviewed by Jack Foley, 1997 April 7; 1; 00:27:47; The program was recorded with the interviewer on the left channel. The interviewee can be heard on the right channel. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399445)
      - Blaeser/Vizenor lecture, 1997 May 22; 1; 01:35:11; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399460)
      - Gerald Vizenor w/ Peter Carroll KPFA, 1996 November; 1; 00:28:10 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399452)
      - Native American Literature Award, undated; 1; 00:43:59; The first four minutes of the program is recorded at a very low level on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399619)
      - Gerald Vizenor, New Letters on the Air, University of Missouri, undated; 1; 00:29:26 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399635)
      - Native American Literature Award / Momaday, Stegner, 1989; 1; 01:18:29 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399551)
      - Interview Tape #1 Helen Jaskoski, 1989 May 4; 1; 01:43:51; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399593)
      - Interview #2 Helen Jaskoski, 1989 May 5; 1; 00:57:39; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The program is in silence from about 47:32 to 47:47 on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399585)
      - "Cover to Cover" KPFA-FM, Gerald Vizenor interviewed by Jack Foley, 1996 August 28; 1; 00:30:01; A warble can be heard at the beginning of the program. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399577)
      - Gerald Vizenor intro by Kimberly Blaeser 10-3-93, 1993 October 3; 1; 00:10:17; The volume fluctuates throughout the program. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399569)
      - Jerry at Wingspread American Indian Voices, undated; 1; 01:01:48; A high amount of buzz and static can be heard on the tape. A high amount of background noise and hum can also be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399544)
      - German Radio, Moccasin Games, Vizenor script, 1992; 1; 00:29:21; High frequency background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399494)
      - 2nd Annual Native American Literature Prize, Paula Gunn Allen, Gerald Vizenor, Terry Wilson, Elaine Jahner, Paula Gunn Allen, 1990 February 13; 1; 01:23:09 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399536)
      - Native American Literature Symposium, Elaine Jahner + Louis Owens, February 13, 1990, UCSC, Boundary Literature with exposition on P. G. Allen + G. Vizenor, 1; 01:29:54 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399528)
      - Gerald Vizenor on NPR's "Morning Edition", 1992 August 24; 1; 00:07:35 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399627)
      - Walter Echo-Hawk, Gerald Vizenor, "Indian Rights vs. Museum Rights", undated; 1; 01:22:32; A buzz can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399486)
      - Native American Short Stories, 1990; 1; 01:24:33 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399510)
      - Gerald Vizenor, In Conversation with Marvin Granger (discussing the trial of Thomas J. Whitehawk), 1972 Fall; 1; 01:01:55; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399502)
        Presented by: Minnesota Public Radio. Runtime: 64:00.
      - Valentine for Leonard Peltier, 2000 February 13; 1; 01:51:17 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399601)
        Included on the audiocassette are Winona LaDuke, Gerald, Vizenor, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Peter Coyote, Joy Harjo, Willie Lone Wolf, Mumia Abu Jamal, Bear Lincoln, Brian Tripp, Mary Youngblood, Agnes Patak (host).
      - Gerald Vizenor on NPR's Morning Edition, "Dead Voices", 1992 August 24; 1; 00:07:28; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399478)
      - The Sound of Writing, Program 72, 73, undated; 1; 00:55:49 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399437)
        A list of contents are included below.
        "Almost Browne"
        "The Rhyme of Reb Nachman"
        "Blind Races"
        "Claybottom Lake"
      - Interior Landscapes, Gerald Vizenor, Library of Congress recording #1 (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990; 1; 01:27:22; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399643)
      - Interior Landscapes, Gerald Vizenor, Library of Congress recording #5 (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990; 1; 01:27:46; The program is distorted at times and static can be heard on the tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091399650)
    - Reel-to-Reel
      - Myles Group, "49 Indians", undated; 1; 00:40:04; Static can be heard on the audiotape reel. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399668)
  - Video Recordings
    - VHS
      - Native American Novelists: Gerald Vizenor, 1995; YCALMSS539_0009; 1; 00:48:59 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349579)
        A biography on Gerald Vizenor is included on the back of the tape. It reads: His life, like his work, was a long time taking root in a place and a culture. Drawing on his Ojibwa heritage, the bitter effects of his father's murder when he was himself still a baby, his intermittent formal education, and his need to reconcile the tribal past with the political present, Vizenor has, poem by poem, story by story, and novel by novel constructed an impressive oeuvre that marks him as among the most prolific and most intellectually challenging writers of the Native American renaissance.
      - "The Right to Identity," Part 1, Feb 1975, First Lecture at Berkeley, 1975 February; YCALMSS539_0010; 1; 00:33:47; This video is in poor condition. The video drops out throughout the tape. The sound is okay. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349587)
      - "The Right to Identity," Part 2, Feb 1975, First Lecture at Berkeley, 1975 February; YCALMSS539_0011; 1; 00:33:13 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349595)
      - "The Right to Identity," Part 3, Feb 1975, First Lecture at Berkeley, 1975 February; YCALMSS539_0012; 1; 00:07:42; The tape was in poor condition. The video does drop out. The audio is okay. The video is in black and white. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349603)
      - "The Red Coin" by Gerald Vizenor, Performed by Kim Blaeser's Literature Class, 1994; YCALMSS539_0013; 1; 00:13:52; Leonard 2nd copy (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349611)
        A handwritten note, dated 1995-10-20, is included with the tape and reads: Hi Jerry, Thanks for the kind message you left about the book. It means a lot to me that you think it's good. And thanks for the copy of "The Writer's Notebook". You know you've made it when people want your bar napkins! I'm sending this tape one of my students made last spring. It's supposed to be a version of your story "The Red Coin". It's odd but you will probably get a kick out of it just the same. All is well here I go home for my Mom's tests next Wednesday. Send good healing energies. Just talked to Gordy and wondered when the three of us might even be in the same place. That would be "good fun" as my mom says. Anyway just wanted to let you know I'm thinking of you. Hi to Laura + Amy. Best, Kim Oh, I almost forgot: HAPPY BIRTHDAY!!
      - Contemporary Native American Authors, Classes 20 & 21, Governors State University 1998 Native Literature Program, YCALMSS539_0014; 1; 01:57:01 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349629)
      - "The Memory of the Flood," Gerald Vizenor, 1993; YCALMSS539_0015; 1; 00:49:14 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349637)
      - "The Memory of the Flood," Film on Vizenor - Italian Narration, 1994; YCALMSS539_0016; 1; 00:49:24 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349645)
      - "Distant Voices...Thunder Words," Gerald Vizenor, Nebraska ETV, 59 min., 1990; YCALMSS539_0017; 1; 01:00:00 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349652)
      - "My Hands are the Tools of My Soul"; TRT: 54, 1975; YCALMSS539_0018; 1; 00:53:34 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349660)
    - U-Matic
      - Harold of Orange (partially mixed music track), 1984; YCALMSS539_0019; 1; 00:34:07; Original 16mm, color (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349678)
    - Video Reel (1/2 inch Memorex, 5 inches)
      - Vizenor, The Right to Identity, Video/23, NASL-AV, No. 1, undated; 1
      - Vizenor, The Right to Identity, Video/23, NASL-AV, No. 2, undated; 1
    - Film Reel
      - Harold of Orange, 16 mm
  - Oversize
    - "Valentine for Leonard Peltier," poster (Box 42)
    - UC Santa Cruz, newspaper (Box 42)
    - Reviews and publications, 4 (Box 42)
    - "The Psychotaxidermist", in The Minneapolis Star, 1978 Jul 29 (Box 42)
    - Native American Indian History Month, University of Illinois, poster, 1988 Oct (Box 42)
    - "One," by Sol Krueger, sheet music, bound (inspired by Vizenor's "Seventeen Chirps"), 1980 (Box 42)
    - Bearheart, covers (Box 42)
    - Griever, covers (Box 42)
    - Crossbloods, covers (Box 42)
    - Interior Landscapes, covers (Box 42)
    - Wordarrows, covers (Box 42)
    - Various titles, covers (Box 42)
    - Covers, proofs and other material (Box 42)
    - Announcements, lectures and literary events featuring Vizenor (Box 42)
    - Minneapolis Tribune articles written by Vizenor, 1968-1969; 17 (Box 43)
    - Berkeley Summer Research Seminars, layout boards (Box 43)
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Reel-to-Reel, Myles Group "49 Indians" (Box 45)
      Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Video Reel, Vizenor, The Right to Identity, Video/23, NASL-AV, No. 1 and 2 (Box 45)
    - Computer disks (Box 46)
      Restricted Fragile. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Film Reel, "Harold of Orange," 16 mm (Box 47 Cold Storage)
- August 2004 Acquisition, 1970-2004; 15.75; (16 boxes)
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2004.
  Box 102 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 701
  - "Trickster Chaos: Old Stories and New Science in the Postindian Novel" by Linda Lizut Helstern, typescript of an academic dissertation re: Gerald Vizenor and others, with cover letter, 216pp, 2001 (Box 49)
  - "Dark River" by Louis Owens, typescript, 289pp, undated (Box 49)
  - "Storied Voices in Native American Texts" by Blanca Chester, typescript of an academic dissertation, 262pp, undated (Box 49)
  - "A Red Girl's Reasoning: Early Native American Women Writers and the Post-Reservation Home, 1883-1927" by Betty Louise Bell, typescript with cover letter, 181pp, 2000 (Box 49)
  - "Writing Circles Around Indian Territory: the Selected Short Stories Cherokee Writer and Editor Ora Eddleman Reed" by Alexia Kosmider, typescript with cover letter, correspondence and photocopies, 616-pp, 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - "Bringing Into Being" edited by Jacquelyn Kilpatrick, typescript of a projected book re: mixed blood novelist and scholar Louis Owens with cover letter and outline, 71pp, 2003 (Box 49)
  - Literary and personal correspondence re: the death of mixed-blood novelist and scholar Louis Owens, who died of a self-inflicted gunshot wound in 2002, approx. 500pp (Box 49)
  - "The Mask Make" by Diane Glancy, typescript dated 9/12/00 and labeled "Revised copy #2" with cover letter, 203pp, 2000 (Box 49)
  - "Designs of the Night Sky" by Diane Glancy, typescript, 148pp, undated (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous literary and academic submissions to the University of Oklahoma Press American Indian Literature and Critical Studies Series, approx. 200pp, 1999-2001 (Box 49)
  - Literary and business correspondence re: University of Oklahoma Press American Indian Literature and Critical Studies Series, plus promotional pamphlets, approx. 500pp, 1999-2002 (Box 49)
  - Royalty statements, 1999 (Box 49)